It depends on the karma, what they
have done here on Earth, you see.
它取决于业力 取决于你在地球上做了什么
Some souls which are very attached
to their material things, they roam around
一些灵魂非常依附于他们的物质享受 他们四处闲逛
until they can realise that
that is not - they are not free.
直到他们可以认识到那不是 他们不是自由的
Like that many souls
have helped a lot.
And the Atma in itself,
when somebody dies
当某人死去时
it goes in different lokas because
it's like a journey. You go,
他去向不同的界 因为它就像一个旅程 你去
you learn something and come back.
Or if you have heavy karma, like I said,
你学到一些东西并回来 或者如果你有很重的业力 就像我说的
that time there and
time here is different.
那里的时间和这里的时间是不同的
So, you will go where you have to,
according to your karma.
所以 你将去到你必须去的地方 根据你的业力
So, it's not - you see, very often
people say, I have heard people say,
所以 它不是 你瞧 通常人们说 我听过人们说
"You know, this
priest has told me
这个神父已经告诉我
that after I die if I have been doing so much
japa, prayer, all these stuff, I will be free."
我已经如此念诵 祈祷了很多 所有的这些事 我死后 我将会自由
And then you live your life
like a savage, you know,
接着你的生活过的像一个野人
and thinking that yes, you will be free because
that priest has told you yes, you will do so much
并认为着是的 你将会自由因为神父已经告诉过你是的 你要念诵很多
japa, then you do everything mechanically,
everything, then you say, yes, you will be free.
接着你机械地做着每一件事 接着你说 是的 你将会自由
You will never be free!
你永远也不会自由
Because freedom is
not attained just like that.
因为自由不是像那样去获得的
That's why I said, you know,
the mind has to surrender.
那就是为什么我说 头脑必须臣服
Otherwise, if that mind is not
surrendered, you can't attain Him.
否则 如果那个头脑不臣服 你不能臻达祂